You’ve studied hard, you’ve got the grades and now you’re off to university!
你努力学习，拿到了满意的成绩，如今即将踏入大学校园！
This is the journey that many students are taking, but how prepared are they to leave home, stand on their own two feet and be self-sufficient?
这是许多学生都会踏上的旅程，但他们是否做好了离家的准备，能否真正独立生活、自给自足呢？
One study, carried out by the Higher Education Policy Institute and Unite Students in 2017, suggested that as well as being excited and nervous, many students are deeply ill-informed about what to expect.
高等教育政策研究所与联合学生公寓在2017年开展的一项研究表明，许多学生在满怀期待与忐忑的同时，对于大学生活的实际情况也知之甚少。
Of course, flying the nest to go to university is the opportunity of a lifetime, but to make the most of it needs some preparation before you arrive.
当然，离家上大学是一生难得的机遇，但要想充分利用这段时光，就需要在入学前做好一些准备。
This means learning life skills such as cooking and cleaning.
这意味着要学习烹饪、打扫这类生活技能。
You’ll no longer be able to rely on Mum and Dad to feed you or clear up after you, so try to learn how to make some staple dishes that are quick and easy to prepare.
你不能再依赖父母为你做饭、收拾残局了，所以不妨学着做几道简单快捷易上手的家常菜。
Graduate Peter Rogers told the BBC: “I didn’t really have anything other than rudimentary cookery skills before I went to university and found learning to cook was reasonably enjoyable.”
毕业生彼得·罗杰斯在接受BBC采访时表示：“上大学前，我只掌握了一些最基础的烹饪技能，后来发现学着做饭其实还挺有意思的。”
Other things to do while at home is to practise some of those household chores, like operating the washing machine or ironing your clothes!
在家时还可以练习一些家务，比如操作洗衣机、熨烫衣物等等！
These domestic skills will come in useful because students will probably be living with others such as in a flat share or shared campus-based accommodation.
这些居家技能迟早会派上用场，因为学生很可能会和别人合租公寓，或是住进校内的集体宿舍。
This will also require taking responsibility for managing their finances because, apart from tuition fees, accommodation is likely to be the biggest cost for students living away from home.
这也意味着学生需要承担起管理个人财务的责任，因为对于离家在外的学生来说，除了学费，住宿费很可能就是最大的开销。
However, the Higher Education Policy Institute and Unite Students study found only about half of the would-be students surveyed identified rent as the biggest expense and concluded that this suggests more should be done to help in the transition between school and university.
但高等教育政策研究所与联合学生公寓的这项研究发现，在受访的准大学生中，只有约半数人认为房租是最大的支出。研究结论指出，这意味着需要采取更多措施，帮助学生顺利完成从中学到大学的过渡。
New students are going to have to be sociable as well – not just relying on old friends at home.
新生还得学会社交——不能只依赖家乡的老朋友。
Going to university requires meeting new people and making new friends.
上大学就意味着要结识陌生人，结交新朋友。
This often begins in Freshers’ Week although journalism student Emmeke Megannety warns that: “People starting uni need to remember that the people you meet in your first week will not necessarily be your friends for life.”
这通常从新生周就开始了，不过新闻系学生埃梅克·梅加内蒂提醒道：“刚开始上大学的人要记住，你第一周遇到的人，未必会成为你一辈子的朋友。”
But whatever your expectations, it’s good to be prepared for the time of your life.
但无论你对大学生活有着怎样的期待，做好充分准备，才能迎接这段人生中最美好的时光。